这是二零二五年广西初中学业水平考试
英语科听力部分。
下。
下面是听力试音时间。
Hi, Mark. I want to have a class party.
Will you help me?
Sure, Alice. So when shall we have the party?
What about Friday afternoon?
We won't have any lessons then.
Good idea. We can all meet and play party games.
Wonderful. I can play the dance music.
I will bring some flowers and paint some pictures for the party.
Nice. And we want different kinds of food.
You're right. We can ask Jackson and Lucy for help.
Okay. Let's start to get ready for the party.
No problem. Hi, Mark.
I want to have a class party.
Will you help me?
Sure, Alice. So when shall we have the party?
What about Friday afternoon?
We won't have any lessons then.
Good idea. We can all meet and play party games.
Wonderful. I can play the dance music.
I will bring some flowers and paint some pictures for the party.
Nice. And we want different kinds of food.
You're right. We can ask Jackson and Lucy for help.
Okay. Let's start to get ready for the party.
No problem. Wonderful.
是因。
到此结束。
听力考试正式开始。
play dance music.
一，听。
听力。
I 1. I often go to school on foot.
一听句子，选图片。
你将听到五个句子，请选出与所听句子内容相符的图片。
有一幅图是多余的。
每个句子读。
1. I often go to school on foot.
2. The monkey is eating a banana.
3. Look, your football is under the chair.
3. Look, is chair.
4. The girl cleans the window every week.
5. Put up your hands if you have questions.
5. up questions.
二，听短对话，选择最佳答案。
你将听到五段对话，每段对话后有
一个小题，请根据。
对话内容：选出最佳答案。
每段对话读两遍。
六，
Lucy, who was that little girl in the photo?
She is my sister Lily.
6. Lucy, who was that little girl in the photo?
7. David, may I borrow your ruler?
Certainly, Linda. Here you are.
8. Peter, what vegetable do you like best?
Carrots. I think carrots are good for my eyes.
9. Mike, how often do you visit your grandparents?
Twice a week.
I always spend time with them, twice a week, no matter how busy I am.
9. Mike, how often do you visit your grandparents?
Twice a week.
I always spend time with them, twice a week, no matter how busy I am.
10. Cindy, what did you do last night?
I saw the latest film in Sky Cinema.
三，听长对话，选择最佳答案。
你将听到三段对话，请根据对话内容选出每个问题的最佳答案。
每段对话读两遍。
请听第一段对话，回答第十一至十三小。
What's the matter with you?
I have a stomachache, doctor.
I I stomachache, stomachache, How long have you been like this?
I have got a stomachache since this morning.
Did you have breakfast this morning?
No. I got up late and I had no time to have breakfast.
That's the problem.
You should have breakfast on time.
Thank you, doctor.
What's the matter with you?
I have a stomachache, doctor.
How long have you been like this?
I have got a stomachache since this morning.
Did you have breakfast this morning?
No. I got up late and I had no time to have breakfast.
That's the problem.
You should have breakfast on time.
Thank you, doctor.
Please Can I help you?
请听第二段对话，回答
第十四至十六小题。
Yes, I have lost my bag in the museum.
When did you lose it?
Two hours ago.
We got some bags.
What color is your bag?
It's blue. Let me take a look.
Yes, there is a blue bag.
You can come and check.
Okay. I will go to check right now.
Thank you. Hello, this is the City Museum lost and found office.
Can I help you?
Yes, I have lost my bag in the museum.
When did you lose it?
Two hours ago.
We got some bags.
What color is your bag?
It's blue. Let me take a look.
Yes, there is a blue bag.
You can come and check.
Okay. I will go to check right now.
Thank you. Tom, what are you going to do tomorrow?
倾听第三段对话，回答第十。
七至二十小题。
I will help my uncle pick oranges on his farm.
Picking oranges? That sounds interesting.
Can I join you?
Certainly. What should I bring?
You'd better bring a hat.
The weather will be sunny tomorrow.
Okay. How far is it?
It is about 10 kilometers from the bus stop near our school.
How can we get there?
We can get there by bus.
Let's meet at 8 a.m.
at our school gate tomorrow.
No problem. Tom, what are you going to do tomorrow?
I will help my uncle pick oranges on his farm.
Picking oranges? That sounds interesting.
Can I join you?
Certainly. What should I bring?
You'd better bring a hat.
The weather will be sunny tomorrow.
Okay. How far is it?
It is about 10 kilometers from the bus stop near our school.
How can we get there?
We can get there by bus.
Let's meet at 8 a.m.
at our school gate tomorrow.
No problem. I am Tina from England.
四，听短文，选择最佳答案。
你将听到一篇短文，请根据短文内容。
选出每个问题的最佳答案。
短文读两遍。
Last summer, my Chinese friends invited me to give a Chinese traditional dancing
show with them.
When we began to practice, I found it was difficult to keep up with their moves.
I was afraid our show wouldn't be successful because of me.
But with my friends' encouragement, I kept practicing hard with them every day.
Slowly, I could keep up with their moves.
At last, we showed the dance as a group successfully at an art festival.
Every one of us shone on the stage.
I felt so happy that I shared my happiness with my parents.
I think that the most important thing in our success is to try our best together to
finish the same task.
Now Chinese traditional dance is my favorite Chinese art.
I am Tina from England.
Last summer, my Chinese friends invited me to give a Chinese traditional dancing
show with them.
When we began to practice, I found it was difficult to keep up with their moves.
I was afraid our show wouldn't be successful because of me.
But with my friends' encouragement, I kept practicing hard with them every day.
Slowly, I could keep up with their moves.
At last, we showed the dance as a group successfully at an art festival.
Every one of us shone on the stage.
I felt so happy that I shared my happiness with my parents.
I think that the most important thing in our success is to try our best together to
finish the same task.
Now Chinese traditional dance is my favorite Chinese art.
am Tina the You need to study hard to get excellent grades in every subject.
五，听短文填信息。
你将听到一篇短。
短文，请根据短文内容，将所缺信息填入答题卡对应的横线上，
每空一词。
短文读三遍。
Also, you need to finish a lot of different and difficult trainings.
What's more, you should complete at least three years of experience work.
All the above are some basic requirements.
Good afternoon, everyone.
I am glad to give a talk about how to become an astronaut.
The following are some basic requirements.
To become an astronaut is not easy.
First, you have to be in perfect health and shape because you will face challenging
working environment.
Besides, you should learn English, science and knowledge about space.
You need to study hard to get excellent grades in every subject.
Also, you need to finish a lot of different and difficult trainings.
What's more, you should complete at least three years of experience work.
All the above are some basic requirements.
Good afternoon, everyone.
I am glad to give a talk about how to become an astronaut.
The following are some basic requirements.
To become an astronaut is not easy.
First, you have to be in perfect health and shape because you will face challenging
working environment.
Besides, you should learn English, science and knowledge about space.
You need to study hard to get excellent grades in every subject.
Also, you need to finish a lot of different and difficult trainings.
What's more, you should complete at least three years of experience work.
All the above are some basic requirements.
This is the end
英。
语听力考试到此结束，
请同学们将听力答案转涂到答题卡上，然后继续做笔试部分的题目。